# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello Everyone, I am Wanggang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Today I an teaching you an easy home style dish
# 小鸡炖蘑菇
Mushroom Chicken stew
# 首先我们准备三黄鸡半只
First, we need to prepare half of a yellow chicken
# 切下鸡翅膀和鸡腿之后剁成小块备用
Chop down chicken wing sand legs, chop them into pieces
# 中途需要将鸡脚趾去除
Meanwhile, we need to cut off the toe nails
# 同学们勿用老鸡否则短时间炖煮不透
Guys, remember do not use old chicken, otherwise the dish will not be fully cooked in a short time
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next step we start preparing the other ingredients
# 准备红薯粉条50克放入盆中加入温水浸泡10分钟
Soak 50g of potato starch noodles into the warm water for 10 minutes
# 准备榛蘑50克放入盆中
Put 50g of wild mushroom into the bowl
# 加入温水浸泡10分钟清洗干净备用
Add warm water soak them for 10 minutes and wash them clean
# 同学们切记榛蘑必须多清洗几遍
Guys, remember to wash the wild mushroom a few extra times to make sure they are clean
# 否则榛蘑中会残留泥沙影响口感
Otherwise, there will be remaining dirt or sand in the wild mushroom and it will cause a poor experience
# 准备生姜20克切成姜片备用
Slice 20g ginger slices
# 准备小葱头几根切成葱段备用
Prepare a few green onions and cut them into inch long pieces
# 碗中加入八角2颗
Put 2 star anise into a bowl
# 加入桂皮1小块
Add 1 cinnamon stick
# 加入香叶1片
Add one piece of bay leaf
# 下一步开始制作
Now we are ready to cook
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
Firstly, we add some water into the wok
# 然后将剁好的鸡块冷水下锅焯水1分钟
Then add the chopped chicken into cold water parboil them for a minute
# 中途加入适量的料酒去腥
Add some Chinese cooking wine to remove unpleasant taste
# 焯好水之后倒出控水备
After boiling, drain the water
# 下一步开始炒制
Next, we start stir frying
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
Heat up the wok then add some oil to grease the wok
# 滑锅的目的是防止鸡肉下锅翻炒时粘锅
The goal of greasing the wok is to prevent the chicken from sticking to the wok
# 热油倒出之后加入适量的底油
After pouring out the heated oil, we add some cold oil
# 油温烧至5成热之后加入准备好的料头和香料爆香
Once the oil gets about halfway boiling, we add and stir fry the ginger, bay leaf, star anise, and the green onions
# 香料爆香之后加入焯好水的鸡肉翻炒1分钟
Once we bring out the aroma of the seasonings, we add the chicken and stir fry for about a minute
# 这一步的目的是将鸡肉炒香炒至明显的收缩
The goal of this step is to fry the chicken until it releases the savory flavor, meanwhile, the meat also shrinks
# 翻炒1分钟之后加入蚝油20克
Stir fry about 1 minute, then we add 20g of oyster sauce
# 加入老抽3克调色
Add 3 grams of dark soy sauce for color
# 加入生抽酱油10克从锅边淋入
Add 10g light soy sauce along the edge of the wok
# 然后翻炒几下将鸡肉炒至上色
Stir fry a bit to color the chicken
# 鸡肉炒至上色之后再加入适量的清水
After coloring the chicken add some water
# 清水的量能没过原料2厘米即可
The amount of water we need is about 2 centimeter above all ingredients
# 大火烧开之后开始调味
Bring it to a hard boil with high heat and season it while boiling
# 锅中加入食用盐1勺（约3克）
Add about a small spoon of salt(3g)
# 加入胡椒粉1勺
Add white pepper powder about a small spoon
# 加入少许白糖
Add a small amount of sugar
# 中途需要再撇去浮沫
In the middle of stewing we need to get rid of the impurity of the soup
# 再加入洗好的榛蘑
Add the clean wild mushroom
# 然后转小火炖20分钟
Stew them with low heat for 20 minutes
# 这一步的目的是炖出鸡肉和榛蘑的香味
The goal of this step is to emerge the flavor of the the chicken and the wild mushroom
# 20分钟之后加入泡好的粉条
20 minutes later we add the soaked noodles
# 将其煮熟煮软即可出锅
Once the noodles are soft, we can serve the dish
# 同学们切记粉条不可煮太久否则容易煮烂
Guys, remember do not cook the noodles for too long or it will become mushy.
# 一道香味浓郁的小鸡炖蘑菇就制作完成
A tasty Mushroom Chicken Stew is finished
# 下面开始技术总结
Now here is the technical summary
第一，小鸡炖蘑菇属于东北名菜之一，其香味和鲜味非常浓郁
First, Mushroom Chicken stew is a famous dish from Northeastern area of China, the umami taste is very strong
# 第二，由于榛蘑中的泥沙比较多所以必须多清洗几遍
# Second, the wild mushroom might be muddy so you need to wash them a few times to make sure they are clean
# 第三，此菜不需要鸡精味精，只需蚝油酱油盐调咸鲜味即可
# Third, we do not need chicken bouillon for this dish, all we need is oyster sauce, soy sauce, oil and salt to enchance the savory taste
# 第四，粉条应在起锅前2分钟下锅，否则容易煮烂
# Fourth, the noodles should go in about 2 minutes before we take the dish out of the wok, or they will get overcooked.
# 鸡肉炖粉条的技术总结完毕
# That’s all for technical summary